Archibald MacLeish Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence, 1907-1981 (Box 1-23)
  - Dietz, Howard, 1941
  - Dillon, George, 1942
  - Donaldson, Norman, 1939-1945
  - Donovan, William J., 1941-1944
  - Dos Passos, John, 1939-1968, undated
  - Douglas, Emily Taft, 1945
  - Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1941-1945
  - Douglas, Melvyn, 1941-1942
  - Douglas, Paul F., 1945
  - Downes, Olin, 1945
  - Drake, Carlos, 1941
  - Drummond, Roscoe, 1945
  - DuBois, Cornelius, 1942-1943
  - Dubos, René, 1967
  - Duell, Charles H., 1944
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1945
  - Dun, Angus, 1945
  - Dunn, J. C., 1941-1945 (Box 7)
  - Durant, Will, 1945
  - Dwiggins, William A., 1945
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1939-1958, undated, (3 folders)
  - Eaker, Ira, 1945
  - Early, Stephen T., 1940-1942
  - Eastman, Max, 1961
  - Eaton, Charles A., 1942-1945
  - Edman, Irwin, 1943-1944
  - Eichelberger, Clark, 1942-1945
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1953
  - Eisenhower, Milton S., 1942, 1968-1975, undated
  - Eliot, George Fielding, 1942-1944
  - Eliot, Thomas Stearns, 1950-1956
  - Elliston, Herbert, 1942-1945
  - Engle, Paul, 1939-1943
  - Ernst, Morris L., 1941-1946
  - Ethridge, Mark, 1944
  - Evans, Luther Harris, 1944-1949
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1935-1968, undated, (4 folders)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, 1944-1949
  - Fairbanks, Douglas, Jr., 1941-1942
  - Farrar, John, 1934-1945 (Box 8)
  - Fast, Howard, 1945
  - Feller, A. H., 1941-1943
  - Ferber, Edna, 1934
  - Field, Marshall, 1943-1945
  - Filene, Lincoln, 1945
  - Finletter, Thomas K., 1945
  - Finley, David, 1944-1945
  - Fischer, Louis, 1943-1945
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1939-1944
  - Fisher, Ham, 1942
  - Fisher, Sterling, 1943-1945
  - Fitts, Dudley, 1932-1967
  - Flemming, Arthur S., 1944-1945
  - Foote, Wilder, 1945
  - Ford, Ford Madox, 1933
  - Ford, Gerald R., 1977, undated
  - Ford, John, 1941
  - Forrestal, James V., 1942-1945
  - Forster, Edward Morgan, 1947-1949
  - Fortune, 1933-1938
  - Foster, Reginald C., 1940-1945
  - Frank, Waldo, 1941
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1939-1964, undated
  - Freeman, Douglas S., 1941-1945 (Box 9)
  - Frost, Robert, 1933, 1957
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1944-1945, 1956
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1937-1977, undated, (4 folders)
  - Gannett, Lewis, 1940
  - George, Walter F., 1942-1945
  - Gildersleeve, Virginia, 1944-1945
  - Graham, Frank P., 1942-1944
  - Greene, Jerome D., 1940-1941
  - Greene, Lorne, 1942
  - Greenwood, C. J., 1936-1937
  - Grew, Joseph C., 1944-1945
  - Grover, Allen, 1941-1946
  - Gunther, John, 1941-1945
  - “H” miscellaneous, 1921-1978, undated
    - “Ha-He”, (3 folders)
    - “He-Hy”, (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Halifax, Edward, 1942-1949
  - Hamburger, Philip, 1943-1944
  - Hammarskjöld, Dag, 1956-1958
  - Hand, Learned, 1942-1956
  - Hansen, Kurt Heinrich, 1948-1949
  - Hanson, Haldore E., 1945
  - Harcourt, Alfred, 1940
  - Harris, Roy, 1941-1943
  - Hassett, William D., 1941-1942
  - Hayden, Carl, 1942
  - Hays, Brooks, 1945
  - Hayward, Walter B., 1942
  - Hecht, Ben, 1945
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1944
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1927-1958, undated, (3 folders)
  - Hemingway, Pauline, 1942
  - Henderson, Leon, 1934, 1941
  - Herter, Christian A., 1942-1944
  - Hill, Edwin C., 1944
  - Hill, Lister, 1942-1945
  - Hindemith, Paul and Gertrude, 1952, undated
  - Hiss, Alger, 1945
  - Hoagland, Edward, 1966-1974
  - Hobson, Laura, 1939-1942
  - Hodgins, Eric, 1936-1940
  - Holmes, Julius C., 1945 (Box 11)
  - Hoover, John Edgar, 1942-1944
  - Hopkins, Harry Lloyd, 1937-1944
  - Hoppenot, Henri, 1944
  - Houghton, Arthur, 1940-1944
  - Houseman, John, 1937
  - Hovde, Bryn, 1945
  - Howe, Quincy, 1945
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1940
  - Hull, Cordell, 1941-1944
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1967-1968
  - Huse, Robert, 1941-1943
  - Hutchins, Robert W., 1945-1946
  - Huxley, Julian, 1956
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1940-1969, undated
  - Ickes, Harold L., 1940-1946
  - Ingersoll, Ralph, 1939-1945
  - Inman, Samuel Guy, 1944
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1920-1973, undated, (2 folders)
  - Jackson, C. D., 1940-1953
  - Jackson, Charles, 1943
  - Jackson, Robert H., 1940-1941
  - Johnson, Louis, 1944
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1945, 1967, undated
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1944-1945
  - Jones, Jesse H., 1944
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1936-1969, undated
    - “Ka-Kor”, (3 folders)
    - “Kos-Ky”, (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Kane, R. Keith, 1941-1944
  - Kazan, Elia, 1963, undated
  - Kazin, Alfred, 1956
  - Kefauver, Estes, 1941-1945
  - Keller, Kent E., 1940
  - Kennedy, John F., 1961
  - Kent, Frank, 1941-1944
  - Keynes, Maynard, 1941-1944
  - Kimball, Fiske, 1945
  - Kintner, Robert E., 1941-1944
  - Kirchwey, Freda, 1940-1945
  - Kirk, Alan G., 1945
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1939-1945
  - Kissinger, Henry A., undated
  - Kittredge, Frank A., 1945
  - Knopf, Alfred, 1945, 1977
  - Knox, Frank, 1941-1942
  - Koussevitzky, Serge, 1944-1948
  - Krock, Arthur, 1945, 1968
  - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1942-1943
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1937-1969, undated, (5 folders)
  - Laderman, Ezra, 1968
  - La Farge, Christopher, 1944
  - La Farge, Oliver, 1942
  - La Guardia, Fiorello H., 1941-1942
  - Lamont, Thomas W., 1942-1944, 1963
  - Land, Emory S., 1941-1942 (Box 13)
  - Landis, James M., 1940-1942
  - Lanux, Pierre de, 1939-1942
  - Larsen, Roy E., 1940
  - Larsson, R. E. F., 1940
  - Laski, Harold J., 1939, 1949
  - Laughlin, Henry A., 1944
  - Laughlin, James, 1963-1968
  - Lee, Muna, 1943-1946, undated, (2 folders)
  - Léger, Alexis Saint-Léger (Saint-John Perse), 1940-1979
  - Leger, Fernand, 1941
  - LeHand, Marguerite, 1939-1941
  - Leigh, Robert, 1945-1946
  - Leland, Waldo, 1944-1945
  - Lerner, Max, 1940-1945
  - Levitas, S. M., 1945
  - Lewis, Wilmarth, 1940-1944
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1941-1944
  - Lilienthal, David E., 1942, 1973-1975, undated
  - Linscott, Robert Newton, 1924-1962, (2 folders)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1937-1963 (Box 14)
  - Livingston, Alexander, 1945
  - Lomax, Alan, 1941
  - Lorraine, Marianne, 1941-1942
  - Lovett, Robert A., 1935-1945
  - Lowe, E. A., 1945
  - Lowell, Robert, 1963-1966
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1942-1945
  - Luce, Henry Robinson, 1939-1965
  - Lydenberg, Harry M., 1941-1945
  - Lyons, Louis, 1940-1946, 1960
  - “M” miscellaneous, 1934-1979, undated
    - “Ma-Mig”, (7 folders)
    - “Mil-My”, (5 folders) (Box 15)
  - MacDowell, Marian (Mrs. Edward MacDowell), 1944
  - MacKaye, Percy, 1939-1941
  - MacLeish, Ada Hitchcock (wife), undated
  - MacLeish, Andrew and Martha (father and mother), 1907-1945, undated
  - MacLeish, Bruce, 1945
  - MacLeish, Kenneth (brother), 1917, undated
  - MacLeish, Kenneth (son) and Carolyn, 1945, 1963-1964, undated
  - MacLeish, Mary Hillard (aunt), 1945
  - McAdoo, Eleanor Wilson, 1944
  - McCloy, John Jay, 1941-1945
  - McCord, David, 1940-1945
  - McDermott, Michael J., 1945
  - McGovern, George, 1968-1972
  - McMahon, Brien, 1945
  - McNutt, Paul V., 1942-1945
  - Makins, Roger, 1945
  - Malamud, Bernard, 1944
  - Malone, Dumas, 1939
  - Malraux, André, 1940
  - Mann, Klaus, 1944
  - Mann, Thomas, 1940-1949
  - Mansbridge, F. Ronald, 1942
  - Maritain, Jacques, 1940-1945
  - Markel, Lester, 1944
  - Marshall, George C., 1944-1948, 1956
  - Massey, Raymond, 1941-1945
  - Mathiessen, F. O., undated
  - Maugham, W. Somerset, 1945
  - Maverick, Maury, 1945
  - Mearns, David C., 1943-1976
  - Mellett, Lowell, 1940-1945
  - Menefee, Selden, 1945
  - Meredith, Burgess, 1941-1942
  - Meredith, William M., 1943-1944, 1969, 1975
  - Merriam, Charles E., 1944
  - Merz, Charles, 1939-1945
  - Messersmith, George S., 1945 (Box 16)
  - Meyer, Agnes, 1940-1945
  - Meyer, Cord, 1945
  - Meyer, Eugene, 1941-1945
  - Millis, Walter, 1941-1942
  - Mills, Saul, 1940
  - Mizener, Arthur, 1937
  - Moore, Douglas, 1942-1944, undated
  - Moore, Marianne, 1950-1962
  - Moore, Merrill, 1932-1942, 1954
  - Morgenstierne, Wilhelm Munte de, 1945
  - Morgenthau, Henry, 1941-1945
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1942, 1963-1975
  - Morrison, Theodore, 1940
  - Moss, Arnold, 1945
  - Mowrer, Edgar A., 1942-1945
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott, 1942-1943, 1961
  - Muir, Willa, 1956-1969
  - Mumford, L. Quincy, 1944
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1944-1945, 1960, 1967
  - Mundt, Karl E., 1945
  - Murphy, Gerald and Sara, 1931-1964
  - Murphy, Robert, 1945
  - Murray, James E., 1946
  - Myers, Howard, 1945-1946
  - Myers, Richard E., 1940-1945
  - “N” miscellaneous, 1937-1968, undated, (2 folders)
  - Nabokoff, Nicholas, 1939-1944
  - Nabokov, Vladimir, 1951
  - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1962
  - Nelson, Donald, 1941-1942
  - Neuberger, Richard L., 1942-1946
  - Nicolson, Harold George, 1935-1938, undated
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1945-1946, 1958
  - Nixon, Richard, 1969
  - Norton, W. W., 1943-1945
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1940-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Odets, Clifford, 1944
  - O'Donnell, John, 1942
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, undated
  - Osborn, Frederick H., 1942-1945
  - Owen, Robert L., 1945
  - “P” miscellaneous, 1934-1981, undated, (5 folders)
  - Parsons, Geoffrey, 1943-1944
  - Pasvolsky, Leo, 1945
  - Paul, Elliot, 1940
  - Pearce, Charles A., 1939-1945
  - Pearson, Drew, 1944
  - Pearson, Norman H., 1937
  - Peattie, Margaret, 1943-1945
  - Peattie, Roderick, 1944-1945
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1942
  - Peirce, Waldo, 1945
  - Pepper, Claude, 1941-1945
  - Perkins, Frances, 1942-1944
  - Perkins, Maxwell E., 1931, 1945 (Box 18)
  - Perkins, Milo, 1942-1945
  - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1942-1945
  - Perse, Saint-John See Alexis Saint-Léger Léger
  - Peyre, Henri M., 1944
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1940-1942
  - Phillips, William, 1941
  - Pinchot, Gifford and Cornelia, 1941-1942
  - Poore, Charles, 1941-1945
  - Popov, Igor, 1967-1974
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1949
  - Porter, Paul, 1944
  - Pottle, Frederick A., 1942-1944
  - Pound, Dorothy, 1945, 1968
  - Pound, Ezra, 1926-1967, undated, (3 folders)
  - Price, Byron, 1941-1945
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J., 1936-1937
  - Pringle, Henry F., 1941-1944
  - Pusey, Nathan M., 1958-1963, undated
  - Putnam, Herbert, 1943
  - Putnam, James, 1940
  - “Q” miscellaneous, 1943-1945
  - “R” miscellaneous, 1934-1979, undated, (7 folders)
  - Rachwiltz, Mary de, 1959-1975 (Box 19)
  - Rayburn, Sam, 1942
  - Reid, Ogden and Helen, 1941-1945
  - Reston, James, 1942-1945, 1969, undated
  - Reynolds, Quentin, 1942
  - Rinehart, Stanley M., Jr., 1939-1944
  - Roberts, Owen J., 1945
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1934
  - Rockefeller, David, 1968
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1942-1945
  - Rodman, Selden, 1940-1945
  - Rohde, Ruth Bryan, 1945
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1941-1949
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1938-1945
  - Roosevelt, James, 1941
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1944
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr., 1940
  - Root, Oren, Jr., 1941
  - Roper, Elmo, 1941-1945
  - Rosenbach, A. S. W., 1942-1944
  - Rosenberg, Anna M., 1941-1942
  - Rosenman, Samuel Irving, 1941-1945
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1942-1945
  - Ross, Charles, 1945
  - Ross, Harold W., 1945
  - Rosten, Leo, 1942-1945
  - Rothchild, Edward S., 1941-1942
  - Rowe, James H., 1941-1942
  - Rowe, L. S., 1944-1945
  - Ruml, Beardsley, 1944-1946
  - Rusk, Dean, 1961
  - “S” miscellaneous, 1932-1978, undated
    - “Sa-Sk”, (7 folders)
    - “Sl-Sz”, (5 folders) (Box 20)
  - Sabath, A. J., 1941-1942
  - Salamanca, Lucy, 1942-1945
  - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1942-1949
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1932-1952
  - Santillana, Dorothy and Giorgio de, 1961-1975, undated
  - Saroyan, William, 1940
  - Sarton, May, 1945, 1963-1968, undated
  - Sawyer, Charles, 1945
  - Sayre, Francis B., 1942-1943
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1888-1965), 1943
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. (b. 1917), 1966, 1973
  - Schuman, William, 1943, 1975-1977
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln, 1942
  - Seferis, George, 1958-1965, undated
  - Seldes, Gilbert, 1941-1942
  - Selznick, David O., 1941-1945
  - Serkin, Rudolf, 1969, undated
  - Seymour, Charles, 1939-1941
  - Shapely, Harlow, 1942-1946
  - Shaw, C. Howland, 1944
  - Sherwood, Robert E., 1940-1945, 1954
  - Shipley, Ruth B., 1944-1945
  - Shirer, William L., 1944-1945
  - Shotwell, James, 1943-1945
  - Shumlin, Herman, 1940-1942
  - Shuster, George N., 1941-1945
  - Simanov, Constantine, 1961
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1941-1942
  - Sioussatt, St. George L., 1944
  - Skouras, Spyros P., 1944-1945
  - Sloan, Samuel, 1939-1944
  - Smathers, William H., 1942 (Box 21)
  - Smith, H. Alexander, 1945
  - Smith, Harold, 1941-1945
  - Soong, T. V., 1940-1941
  - Spender, Stephen, 1962, undated
  - Stanton, Frank, 1941
  - Stassen, Harold E., 1941-1945
  - Steinbeck, John, 1940-1945
  - Stettinius, Edward R., 1942-1949
  - Stevens, Wallace, 1951
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1965), 1942-1969
  - Stevenson, Adlai E., Jr. (b. 1930), 1975
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1942-1943
  - Stewart, James, 1945
  - Stimson, Henry Lewis, 1942-1948
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1940
  - Stout, Rex, 1944
  - Stowe, Lyman Beecher, 1941-1942
  - Street, Julian, 1941-1945
  - Studebaker, John, 1941-1944
  - Sullivan, Mark, 1945
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1945
  - Sweetser, Arthur, 1942-1945
  - Swing, Raymond, 1941-1945
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1941-1945
  - “T” miscellaneous, 1939-1977, undated, (4 folders)
  - Taft, Charles P., 1942-1945
  - Taft, Robert A. (1889-1953), 1942-1944
  - Tate, Allen, 1941-1952, 1961
  - Taylor, Deems, 1941-1944 (Box 22)
  - Taylor, Francis, 1944
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1940-1946
  - Thompson, Malvina C., 1942-1945
  - Thomson, Charles A., 1940-1946
  - Tinker, Chauncey B., 1943-1945
  - Tolstoy, Ilia, 1942
  - Torre, Guillermo de, 1941
  - Trammell, Niles, 1941-1945
  - Trout, Robert, 1937
  - Truman, Harry S., 1945-1951
  - Tuchman, Barbara W., 1968, 1979
  - Tully, Grace, 1941-1945
  - Turner, Ralph E., 1944
  - Tuttle, Emerson, 1939-1945
  - Tydings, Millard E., 1941-1942
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1941-1946, undated
  - Udall, Stewart L., undated
  - Underwood, Pierson, 1940
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1935-1944, 1961
  - Utley, Clifton, 1945
  - “V” miscellaneous, 1937-1976, undated, (2 folders)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1945
  - Van Doren, Charles, 1955-1959, 1975
  - Van Doren, Irita, 1944-1945
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1940-1971, undated
  - van Loon, Henrik Willem, 1939-1942
  - Voorhis, Jerry, 1942-1945
  - “W” miscellaneous, 1937-1977, undated, (7 folders)
  - Wagner, Robert R., 1942-1945 (Box 23)
  - Walker, Charles Rumford, 1923-1924, 1941, 1980, undated
  - Walker, Frank, 1942
  - Walker, John, 1944
  - Wallace, Henry Agard, 1941-1945
  - Wallgren, Mon C., 1941-1942
  - Wanger, Walter, 1940-1945
  - Warburg, James P., 1941-1945
  - Ward, Barbara, 1955, 1966
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1945
  - Watson, Edwin M., 1942-1943
  - Watson, Thomas J., 1944-1945
  - Weeks, Edward, 1939-1945
  - Weill, Kurt, 1942
  - Weiss, Louis S., 1939-1945
  - Welles, Orson, 1944
  - Welles, Sumner, 1941-1945
  - West, James E., 1942
  - Wheeler, Monroe, 1944-1945
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1945
  - White, Walter, 1942
  - White, William Allen, 1940
  - Wickard, Claude R., 1942
  - Wiese, Otis, 1939-1940
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1942-1951, undated
  - Wilkins, Roy, 1942
  - Williams, Eric, 1963, undated
  - Williams, Oscar, 1943-1945
  - Williams, Wheeler, 1942
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1939-1940, 1951
  - Willkie, Wendell L., 1942-1944
  - Winant, John G., 1942-1945
  - Winnick, Roy H., 1979, undated
  - Woollcott, Alexander, 1935-1942
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1944
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr., 1952-1976, undated
  - “Y” miscellaneous, 1937-1974, undated
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 1934-1944
  - “Z” miscellaneous, 1940-1945
  - Unidentified, 1937-1979, undated
- Literary File, 1919-1978 (Box 24-39)
  Handwritten and typewritten drafts, correspondence, trial lines, printed copies, notes and worksheets, outlines, notebooks, proofs, and miscellaneous items relating to plays, poetry, prose pieces, screenplays and scripts, and books.
  Arranged by type of material and alphabetically by title therein, except for the notebooks, which are arranged chronologically.
  - Books (Box 24)
    - The American Cause, 1941
    - Changes in the Weather, proposed collection of essays
    - Paris Years, proposed autobiography
    - Poetry and Opinion, 1950
    - Selections for an anthology
  - Drama
    - Aid Raid, verse play for radio, 1938
    - The American Story, verse play for radio, 1944
      - Correspondence
      - Episodes
        - 1-3, (3 folders)
        - 4-10, (7 folders) (Box 25)
      - Miscellany
    - An Evening's Journey to Conway, Massachusetts, 1967
    - Conquistador, verse play for radio, adapted by D. G. Bridson, 1952
    - The Fall of the City, verse play for radio, 1937
      - Correspondence
      - Translations, French and German (Box 26)
    - The Great American Fourth of July Parade, verse play for radio, 1975, (2 folders)
    - Henry, review for music
    - Herakles, 1967
      - Correspondence
      - Manuscript and typescript drafts, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 27)
      - Worksheets
    - J.B., 1958
      - Drafts and worksheets, (2 folders)
      - Motion picture proposal (Box 28)
      - Printed copy
    - Panic: A Play in Verse, 1935
    - Scratch, 1971
      - Correspondence
      - Galley proof
      - Manuscript and typescript drafts
        - Master copies, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 29)
        - Printer's copy
        - Rehearsal scripts, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 30)
      - Miscellany
      - Notes and worksheets
      - Outlines (Box 31)
      - Set designs
    - The Secret of Freedom, play for television, 1959
    - The States Talking, verse play for radio, 1941
    - This Music Crept By Me Upon the Waters, 1953
    - The Trojan Horse, verse play for radio, 1952
    - Union Pacific, ballet, produced 1934
    - Untitled plays and fragments
  - Notebooks
    - 1919-1920's (Cambridge and Paris notebooks), notes and drafts of poems published in The Happy Marriage (1924) and material for Einstein (1929)
    - 1924-1925 (Paris notebook), notes and drafts of poems for Streets of the Moon (1926), including Ars Poetica, The Silent Slain, The Immortal Helix, and 1892-19__ and material for The Pot of Earth (1925) (Box 32)
    - 1926, notes and drafts for The Hamlet of A. MacLeish (1928) (3 vols.) and material for New Found Land (1930)
    - 1926-1930's (Persia notebook) trial lines and drafts, including some for New Found Land
    - 1928-1930's, Notes and drafts, including Conquistador (1932), Public Speech (1936), and Frescoes for Mr. Rockefeller's City (1933)
    - 1929, Notes during Mexican trip for Conquistador.
    - Late 1920's, Trial lines and notes, including Panic (1935), Public Speech, and The Woman on the Stair
    - 1933, Notes and drafts, including Frescoes for Mr. Rockefeller's City (1933)
    - Late 1930's-late 1940's, Drafts and trial lines, including America Was Promises (1939) and Actfive (1948) (Box 33)
    - 1948 (?), Notes and drafts
    - Undated, Drafts of plays, including The Fall of the City
  - Poetry
    - Collections and selections
      - Actfive and Other Poems, 1948
      - America Was Promises, 1939 See also Container 43, America Was Promises
      - The Collected Poems of Archibald MacLeish, 1963
      - New and Collected Poems, 1917-76, 1976
      - Public Speech, 1936
    - Poems
      - Alien
      - Ars Poetica
      - At the Lincoln Memorial
      - At the University Memorial in the Year 1976 (Box 34)
      - Baccalaureate
      - The Ballad of Jabez Stone
      - The Ballad of the Devil Over the Water
      - Bird Watching
      - The Black Day
      - The Blow Flies
      - Bold Venture
      - Bronze
      - The Carrion Crow
      - Celestial Politics
      - Chartres
      - Colloquy for the States
      - Conversation in a Belfry
      - Conway Burying Ground
      - Correction
      - Critics on the Lawn
      - Definitions of Old Age
      - The Deserted Island
      - Discovery of This Time
      - Dozing on the Lawn
      - The Enchantment
      - Epiepithalamion
      - Faith
      - Family Group
      - For Remembrance
      - The Free Men's Song
      - Freedom's Land (song lyric)
      - Geography of This Time
      - A Good Man in a Bad Time
      - Hands
      - The Happy Marriage
      - Hebrides
      - The Hero of Hollywood
      - Hunters
      - Hypocrites
      - Immortal Autumn
      - In and Come In
      - The Infinite Reason
      - Kenneth
      - Kinds of Fire
      - Lines for a Prologue
      - Long Hot Summer
      - Mark Van Doren and the Brook
      - Mayan
      - Midsummer Dawn
      - Nat Bacon's Bones
      - National Security
      - New England Weather
      - Night Watch in the City of Boston
      - The Old Grey Couple (1)
      - The Old Grey Couple (2)
      - Old Photograph
      - Old Time Locals
      - The Old Time White House and the Bright New Gate
      - Omniscience
      - Pablo Casals
      - Perhaps I've Not Seen Shelley Plain
      - Photograph Album
      - Poem for a Festival of Art at the Boston Public Gardens
      - A Poet Speaks From the Visitors' Gallery
      - Population Explosion
      - The Pretty Girl Ballad
      - Private Character and Private Man
      - Reproach to Dead Poets
      - The Revenant
      - Seeing
      - The Sheep in the Ruins
      - The Spanish Dead
      - State Funeral: March 31, 1969
      - TV Commercial
      - A Talk With Laurens Hammond
      - Three Riddles With One Answer
      - The Thrush in the Gaelic Islands
      - To the Tune of Walsingham
      - Two Poems From the War
      - Two Women Talking
      - Voyage to the Moon
      - Voyage West (Box 35)
      - What Killed the Bullfinch House on Beacon Hill
      - White-Haired Girl
      - Years Ago
      - You, Andrew Marvell
      - The Young Dead Soldiers
    - Unidentified
    - Printed copies
  - Prose
    - About a Trespass on a Monument, New York Times, 7 Dec. 1958
    - The Age of Adolescence, Boston Globe, 19 Dec. 1973
    - The Alternative, Yale Review, June 1955
    - The American Writers and the New World, Yale Review, Sept. 1941
    - April Elegy, Atlantic Monthly, June 1945
    - Archibald MacLeish Answers Fifteen Vital Questions, Look, 14 July 1942
    - The Art of the Good Neighbor, Nation, 10 Feb. 1940
    - ASCAP and the Arts, undated
    - The Beginning of Things, undated
    - Books in Wartime, New York Times, 6 Dec. 1942
    - The Conquest of America, Atlantic Monthly, Aug. 1949
    - The Cranbrook Show, undated
    - Declaration of Faith, 1940
    - Evangelism in Verse, undated
    - Football Piece, undated
    - Forewords
      - For an exhibition of photographs by Therese Bonney, 15 Nov. 1940
      - Book on Stephen Vincent Benét, 1978
      - Collection of prose pieces, 1977
      - Age of Change, edited by Robert Wernick
      - The Estate of Poetry by Edwin Muir
      - Fortress of Freedom by Lucy Salamanca (Box 36)
      - Immediate Sun by Rosemary Thomas
      - Catalog of an exhibition by An American Group, Inc., Jan. 1943
      - Catalog of the Stanley Family Exhibition, Feb. 1944
    - The Golden Calf, undated
    - The Humanities and the Defense of the Republic, undated
    - The Inevitable War, undated
    - Instructions of the Librarian of Congress, 1 Oct. 1944
    - Interventions for The Play of Herod, 1969
    - Introductions
      - Byron Price at the Library of Congress, [May 1945?]
      - Book of children's stories by Muna Lee
      - Cultural Relations by Muna Lee
      - Eloges and Other Poems by Saint-John Perse
      - The Last Men of the Revolution by Elias B. Hillard, edited by Wendell D. Garret
      - Our Singing Country by Alan and John Lomax
      - The Year of Peril by Thomas Hart Benton, Mar. 1942
  - Prose
    - Is Mr. Lincoln Dead? undated
    - Jefferson (Thomas) Bicentennial, 1943, (3 folders)
    - The Knowable and the Known, undated
    - Library of Congress Employee Relations Program, Personnel Administration, May 1943
    - Lilienthal's Atomic Energy, undated
    - Looking Jefferson in the Eye, New York Times, 17 June 1973